# Sabrina R. Castro

1035 N Stafford Street, Arlington VA 22201 | (702) 217-8929 | sabrinarcastro@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/sabrinarcastro/

#### **SUMMARY**

Data scientist with over 5 years of federal consulting experience building data visualizations, conducting data analysis and using machine learning to support data driven decision-making. Four years of experience leading multifaceted teams of technical and subject matter experts in the development of predictive models, statistical analysis, reporting, visualizations and data mining.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc.,** Washington, D.C.

01/2019 - Present

- Lead Data Scientist
  - Supported development of project charter and plan as Deputy Project Manager to guide development of a suite of Fraud Risk Assessment frameworks and tools for enterprise-wide and comprehensive programmatic fraud risk evaluations in support of the Bureau of the Fiscal Service's Enterprise Fraud Risk Management Program
  - Requirements gathering, analysis and total cost of ownership assessments to inform the
    procurement and deployment of enterprise-wide data service tools and products in support of
    Data Operations for the Health and Human Services' Office of the Inspector General (HHS OIG)
  - Management of a technical team in the assessment of and deployment of data service solutions
    including migration from legacy systems, expansion and updates to existing tools and products,
    including testing and oversight of operations and maintenance of geospatial analysis, statistical analysis
    and data visualization tools
  - Build work plans and manage interdepartmental collaboration within HHS OIG to ensure successful deployment of data assets and analytical products in an agile environment
  - Mentored and managed career development for my administrative team including setting promotion timelines and skills development goals and provided feedback and facilitated goal setting for project team members

**Kearney and Company, P.C.,** Alexandria, VA Consultant

05/2017 - 01/2019

06/2018 - 01/2019

05/2017 – 05/2018

Senior Analyst

- Lead an agile scrum team in collaborating with program administrators and leaders to evaluate
  operational data and develop reporting solutions to facilitate program oversight including Tableau
  visualizations and workbooks, financial reports and analytic tools to reduce reporting burden for staff in
  support of the Bureau of the Fiscal Service's DATA Act program
- Internal analytics support including data quality assessment and analytic services for Fiscal Service and agency partners to leverage federal spending, operational and administrative agency data to inform better decision-making
- Developed analysis linking federal USAspending data to personnel spending data using R deployed in AWS (EC2) and designed visualization tools that allow members of the public to explore government employment data using Plotly
- Used time-series models to explore the relationship between congressional budget actions and federal
  contract spending. Developed a series of machine learning models in R and lead the design and
  development of a webpage, using D3, and white paper to visualize model results and methodology

Data Analyst

- Lead an initiative to redesign investment portfolio oversight tools, working with Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Office of the Federal Chief Information Officer portfolio managers to identify key metrics and reporting components to expedite the monthly reporting process
- Provided quarterly Information Technology (IT) investment performance reports and created data visualizations to support oversight of cabinet-level agency investments and projects using MySQL, R and Excel
- Conducted data analysis to support policy implementation on behalf of various Executive Office IT
  initiatives, gathering and cleaning financial data using MySQL and R, providing executives summaries
  and client briefings on results

# **Summit Consulting, LLC,** Washington, DC Consultant

04/2014 - 10/2016

Senior Analyst

01/2016 - 10/2016

Analyst 04/2014 - 12/2015Led \$1.3 million project to assist the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund in developing

and operationalizing tools to improve federal credit program administration, risk and compliance

monitoring processes

 Developed a suite of financial risk metrics to evaluate community development financial institutions and developed risk assessment tools to facilitate monitoring and rating these institutions on capital and portfolio risk as well as overall institutional health

- Guided collaborative work with subject matter experts and agency leaders to operationalize a strategy
  for improving program administration including the integration of new tools including development of
  prototype interactive reporting tools using R Shiny to support program operations and oversight
- Conducted data analysis and developed random forest and logit models in R using administrative, loan and financial statement data to estimate financial risk rating models
- Analyzed program budget and operations data to estimate the impact of proposed legislative changes on program administration costs, staffing resources and projected the current and alternate timelines for completing program evaluations under each statutory scenario

# **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

Capital Choice Financial, Associate BusinesSuites, Client Service Coordinator 11/2012 - 04/2014

03/2010 - 09/2011

#### **EDUCATION**

MS Development Economics, University of Sussex, 2012 BA Economics, University of Redlands, 2009

#### **TECHNOLOGIES AND ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Advanced R: Machine learning, data analytics and visualization in R (Desktop and AWS) and RShiny Advanced Stata: Data mining, wrangling, sampling and statistical analysis Some Experience in Python, PostgreSQL (PgAdmin), D3 (JavaScript Library) and Tableau

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Scrum Master